Maurice Smith "Smith Reesie"

Brooklyn, NY 11237 | Linkedin | 1(347) 741-2552 | Email

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Leveraging creative analytics and problem-solving skills as a FullStack Software Engineer gifted at translating basic client requirements into technical development plans. Motivated to advance and expand my skill set through targeted mentorship and large scale projects. Experienced in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, and Bootstrap programming.

WHO IS MAURICE

Through my experiences as a Professional Dancer, Model, and Artistic Director I have acquired strong skills in team-leading and project management. Looking to combine my creative artistry with the ever-evolving world of technology.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Floreo Labs Brooklyn, NY

Consultant / Fullstack Developer

03/2022 - Present

- Contribute to the development of *Black Everything* an RSS feeder, search engine, & database that enables community growth, giving the underrepresented community a beacon for social and economic connectivity. Directly collaborate with multiple project managers and contribute to the stylistic & functional evolution of the active platform
- Designed and integrated integral UX systems that enhance the experience of over 100,000 users by designing a smooth user friendly UI

NIA Community Services Network

Brooklyn, NY

Program Director / Dance Instructor

02/2015 - 09/2021

- Orchestrated and structured after-school activities for a student body of 150 and staff.
- Efficiently logged and stored all data required to run a safe and functional learning/work environment.
- Choreographed weekly dance routines for grades K-5/6-8
- Assisted students with homework and other academic task

J. Crew New York, NY

Retail – Sales Associate

05/2015 - 09/2016

- Helped clients look and feel their best by choosing and coordinating outfits
- Efficiently handled customer's online shipping orders increasing production time by 20%

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Black Everything <u>Test drive</u>

It is a black owned community based web tool(search engine) that gathers(aggregates) information, Selects(curates) multimedia from different sources and centralizes black content all at your fingertips. BlackEverything.com is the destination spot for all things Black,Past, Present, and Future all in one place. There is no need to search for "Black" anything, all your search results will come back Black Everything.

Death to Dad Jokes Github | Demo

A JavaScript web app that allows users to love/hate some of the chring-iest jokes ever written. Utilized ReactJS to fetch from an existing API of dad jokes. The jokes are then displayed one at a time, with the option to reveal the punchline by pressing an additional button.

Implemented a "tally marks" system to count liked vs disliked jokes. Marks are grouped by 5 dynamically.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School New York, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

10/ 2021 - 01/2022 Brooklyn, NY

Coursework - Communications

09/2012 - 05/2016

[SKILL SUMMARY]:

Brooklyn College

JavaScript ReactJS Rails Ruby on Rails HTML5 CSS

Tailwind CSS Google Suite Trello Project Management Team Development